Dhruvi Sakariya

dhruviskr@gmail.com

+91 9867543879

Profile: Full Stack Software Engineer

Summary: Full-stack web software engineer with industry experience in building web applications. Specialization in JavaScript and Typescript language with have professional experience in working with Angular 4 +, AngularJs, NodeJs and with database sources like Mysql and MongoDB. Efficiently delivering a high-quality product and taking up the responsibility and complete ownership from product to business sign-off

About Me: A consistent performer by taking up the responsibility of constantly delivering high-quality products and taking complete ownership from product to business sign off by achieving all my metrics and targets on time without being competitively overdriven. I have the ability to calmly analyse a situation or a task or a problem statement. I have been inquisitive in acquiring knowledge in other fields too. Honesty and Hardwork have always been my best qualities whether in personal or professional life. Compatible with an agile environment and a quick learner.

Career History:

Software Development Engineer at Gaia Smart Cities , July 2020 to present

- Responsible for creating and enhancing Front End applications in typescript using Angular 4 + Framework with HTML and CSS.
- Continuously creating and developing projects for the Smart Cities of India(Agra,Bhopal,Mumbai,Jaipur) with the help of the State Government, which helps in addressing its local citizen's problems with respect to infrastructure,cleanliness,hygiene and other issues digitally,by having a user based interface which can be used for displaying all the relevant information to its workers and to provide appropriate actions through the web portal for resolving such issues.
- Worked on a US government based project called 211 for Pennsylvania State, which helped the
 officers and its workers address and understand the issues digitally of its citizens. It was a
 user-based application wherein a person residing in the particular state could make use of this
 application for any related queries.
- Parallely learning and working as a web designer for the websites of the company.
- Developed scalable performance-oriented applications.
- Efficiently delivering a high-quality product and taking up the responsibility of full ownership from product to business sign-off.

Software Engineer at FlexiLoans, August 2018 to June 2020(1 year 11 months) Mumbai Area,India

- Responsible for creating and enhancing a backend application programming interface from the server to the client in a microservice architecture.
- Fulfilling the product/business requirement through frontend programming logic using Javascript and AngularJs language.
- Solely handling and owning the Bank Parsing module for Flexiloans Technologies Pvt Ltd, for automating the parsing of the bank statements shared, using third party API integration with Perfice and Fin360 as vendors. Improving and building the module to be more efficient, this to fasten up the process and working on to make it a bug-free process.
- Efficiently delivering a high-quality product and taking up the responsibility of full ownership from product to business sign-off.

GIS Analyst at HERE Technologies, July 2017 - August 2018 (1 year 2 months) Mumbai Area, India

- Worked as a GIS (Geographic Information System) Analyst in HERE technologies from July 2017 to August 2018.
- Worked on the Map Making tool to generate roads for autonomous driven vehicles.
- Responsible for achieving daily goals and objectives.

Skills:

- Javascript
- HTML
- CSS
- Angular 4+
- AngularJS
- NodeJs
- MYSQL
- MongoDb
- Kafka
- GitHub
- Jenkins
- AWS (API Gateway)
- WinScp

Education:

- Bachelor of Science in Information Technology from Mumbai University (K.C. College of Education 2014 - 2017) with CGPA 5.90
- Currently pursuing a Part -time MBA (Post Graduate degree) in IT from KJ Somaiya Institute of Management.